Lane Katris

lanekatris@gmail.com (304) 532 0462 https://lanekatris.com

Innovative Full Stack Developer with 9 years experience with microservices, distributed systems, relational and search databases, and the latest UI frameworks. Personally I enjoy learning and working with IoT/hardware projects. Outside of work you'll catch me rock climbing, playing disc golf, or basketball.

GitHub lanekatris

SKILLS

DISTRIBUTED SYSTEMS	Microservices, RabbitMQ, GCP Pub/Sub
WEB DEVELOPMENT	React, GraphQL, Angular 1.x
DEV OPS	Kubernetes, Cloud Build, AppCenter, Shippable, GitHub Actions
DATABASES	SQL Server, Postgres, Mongo, Elasticsearch, Solr, Redis
MOBILE DEVELOPMENT	React Native
LANGUAGES/OTHER	Node.JS/Typescript, C#, Electron, GoLang

EXPERIENCE

The Community Company

Full Stack Developer Dec 2018 - Present

All-remote invite only community providing forums, directories, article authorship, etc.

- Full stack development with React, GraphQL, Postgres and Elastic Search
- Worked with microservice architecture with Apollo Federation and pub/sub messaging
- Facilitated React native application submissions to the app stores along with feature creation and roll outs with OTAs

Marietta Memorial Hospital

Software Developer Apr 2017 - Oct 2018

Integrated development experience along with taking on a business intelligence role to deliver visualizations and tools to help patients and stakeholders

- Built and designed desktop and mobile apps using Electron and React-Native to serve Tableau visualizations to doctors and staff. We supported Windows and OSX. These helped doctors see more patients effectively and allowed them to review their RVUs in real time among other metrics
- Administered an in-house Kubernetes cluster on bare metal. Our applications were available behind our ingress with TLS termination. We used config maps and NFS volume claims to persist data

- Multiple React/Node.js and GoLang web applications served up our GraphQL/REST endpoints and executables. These included a purchase requisition application that processed millions of dollars; along with SQL utilities that split up datasets consumed by stored procedures for SQL reports
- Created Tableau dashboards that showed appointments, cash on hand, and multiple internal dashboards pertaining to project management, backups, etc.
- Utilized Redis cacheing. ElasticSearch was primarily used for structured logging, along with auditing user actions

Fluor BWXT

Software Developer Aug 2016 - Apr 2017

Government contractor building in house eCommerce applications

- Evaluated requirements, architected, and built a reusable REST, API driven sequential workflow engine that allowed certain roles to edit particular data on item procurement requests
- Designed the database schema, API, and Single Page Application for an item catalog from scratch. This
 included complex search functionality based on "preferred" items along with their categorization using
 ASP.Net and SQL Server
- Assessed existing applications to provide estimates on level of effort to get them finished and deployed to clients; along with estimates on implementing functionality to integrate with other applications on site
- Worked with multiple stakeholders to change/create requirements to create an optimal user experience for a faster process for procuring items to gain the best chance of user adoption
- Introduced methodologies and best practices such as SOLID to limit code debt and deliver features quickly to our customers

nChannel

Software Developer Mar 2012 - Aug 2016

Multi-channel eCommerce integration provider with a startup culture. Helped sync orders, items, and inventory between Amazon, eBay, RMS, etc.

- Led a project with supplier order integration; moving orders across accounts to their respective supplier accounts using C#, XSLT, Windows Workflow and Entity Framework
- Integrated and customized the ASPDNSF presentation layer and WSI along with implementing Solr for product / category / pricing search ability. Optimized Solr indexes to support customer SKUs and general search requirements
- Had a DevOps hat consisting of deployments of web applications, server configuration, SQL migrations, along with scripting deployment automation
- Developed web applications from end-to-end, utilizing SQL and NoSQL, Asp.NET MVC / Web API, and Angular JS

West Virginia University at Parkersburg

Computer Support Technician Dec 2010 - Feb 2013

- Facilitated students and faculty with access to network information systems
- Implemented hardware upgrades
- One-on-one assistance with students and the public with technical issues

VOLUNTEERING

Jackson County Animal Shelter

Volunteer Apr 2012 - Jul 2012

EDUCATION

West Virginia University at Parkersburg

Jul 2009 - Apr 2013 Bachelor of Applied Technology - Network Engineering GPA: 3.9

AWARDS

A+ Certification CompTIA